

CONTACT

shaker.khandaker@studenti.unitn.it

✓ shaker@khandakerrahin.com

+39 3517878556

Via della Malpensada 90, 38123 Trento, Italy

in www.linkedin.com/in/khandakerrahin

github.com/khandakerrahin

www.khandakerrahin.com

EXPERTISE

- · Web Application
- Software Development
- Android Apps
- Statistical analysis and computing
- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Processing large data sets
- Data Visualization
- Mathematics
- Big Data
- Data Mining
- Audio Engineering

TOOLS

- Eclipse
- Apache Spark
- Android Studio
- ggplot2
- Wildfly 23
- Jupyter
- MySQL Workbench Matplotlib
- JMeter
- Scikit-learn

LANGUAGES

- English(Professional)
- · Bengali(Native)
- Deutsch(Basic)

SHAKER MAHMUD KHANDAKER

Data Science Student | Software Developer | Musician

A Data Science student with 3 years of experience in Software Development, passionate about exploring new technology and love to compose music.

I am inquisitive about this universe's mysteries, which I want to unravel through my work and even take it a step further by contributing in the field to understand the universe a bit better.

Field of Interest: Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence, Internet of Things, Robotics, Software Engineering, Music.

EDUCATION

MASTER DEGREE IN DATA SCIENCE

University of Trento - Italy

2021 - present

Exploring theoretical, methodological and technical knowledge in mathematics and statistics, computer science in the treatment of data, and in their analysis.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE & ENGINEERING

BRAC University - Bangladesh

2014 - 2018

During university life along with study curriculum of Computer Science, I participated in numerous Robotics Competitions.. I have CGPA 3.09 out of 4.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Spider Digital Innovation

1 Jan 2020 - 15 Jul 2020

- Lead all phases of Java EE web product development.
- Performed responsibilities of reviewing and clarifying business requirements for new application development.
- Reviewed technical solutions/designs prepared by junior engineers.
- Contributed for reviewing and gathering requirements for various software modules.

JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Spider Digital Commerce

19 Feb 2018 - 31 Dec 2019

- Participated in full development lifecycle of web application using JBoss and Spring framework.
- Designed back-end of web application with J2EE and Servlets
- Created RESTful APIs for increased scalability of application
- Designed, configured and maintained MySQL database
- Designed, built, deployment, debug & maintenance of Android applications for Google play.
- Integrated Facebook, Google and other open source APIs within applications.
- · Executed processes for installation and maintenance of Apache Web server and JBoss Application server.

SKILLS

Machine Learning

- Supervised Learning, Unsupervised Learning
- Sci-kit Learn, OpenCV
- Google Cloud Platform
- Pytorch

Programming Language

- Java
- Python
- C++
- PHP

Front-end Technology

- ReactJS, React Native
- Bootstrap
- JQuery
- AJAX
- HTML5, CSS3

Database Technology

- MySQL
- OracleDB
- Firebase

Framework, Server

- · Wildfly, JBoss
- · Tomcat, Apache
- Google Cloud Platform
- Wordpress

API

- RESTful web service
- SOAP web service
- Google APIs

Version Control

- GitHub
- BitBucket

Methodology

- Agile Software Development
- Test-Driven Development
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Pair Programming

REFERENCES

Thesis Supervisor

Dr. Jia Uddin

Assistant Professor | Woosong University jia.uddin@bracu.ac.bd

Team Lead

Md Intekhabul Hafiz

Software Development Lead | Spider Digital Innovation

+8801924400893 | mihafiz@gmail.com

PUBLICATIONS

A M Muntasir Rahman, Shaker M. Khandaker, Nasif Noor Saleheen Arnob and Md. Ashraful Alam, <u>"A Portable Refreshable Braille Display using Micro Servos"</u>, submitted in 7th International Conference on Informatics, Electronics & Vision, Japan.

PROJECTS

- Image Search Engine: Trained a CNN Model from scratch, experimented with Keras pre-trained models and implemented Transfer Learning.
- <u>Challenge:</u> Business Analytics for a Sustainable Telecommunication Market (blended)
- <u>Data Mining:</u> Therapy Recommendation System based on Hybrid and Item-Item Collaborative Filtering.
- <u>Bag of Visual Words(BoVW)</u> image classification using SIFT/ORF Machine Learning algorithm.
- <u>Lebupay:</u> Proactively worked on Online Payment Gateway
 and its development and to improve gateway's functionality
 and improve security system with regular monitoring.
 <u>Technology used:</u> Java, JSP, Spring Framework, Wordpress.
- <u>Bubble.fyi:</u> Worked as one of the backend developers of Bulk SMS platform and developed RESTful APIs for SMS services.
 <u>Technology used:</u> Java, Jboss, MySQL, RESTful Web Services, PHP
- WeTopUp: Participated in full development lifecycle of Mobile Recharge Platform with <u>Android app</u>. Worked as the Lead backend developer while implementing scalable Microservices. Also designed, configured and maintained MySQL database. <u>Technology used</u>: <u>Java</u>, <u>Jboss</u>, <u>JSP</u>, <u>MySQL</u>, <u>RESTful Web Services</u>, <u>PHP</u>
- School IoT Attendance Solution: Complete School
 Attendance Solution with RFID which provides contact-less detection of student entry/exits and SMS alerts to guardians.
 Also, It provides Real-time student attendance activity monitoring. Technology used: Java, C#, MySQL Procedures, RESTful Web Services, PHP
- <u>Email server</u>: An email server which provides APIs to web applications to send email, notifications and alerts.
 <u>Technology used</u>: *Java, Jboss, MySQL, RESTful Web Services, PHP*

CREATIVE WORKS

The Void

A composition inspired by the void, tells a summarized story of the loss and sufferings caused due to the COVID-19 pandemic.

Love Story

Composed by Francis Lai. Experimental arrangements by Rahin.